（ヒナタ）魂の位置さえわかれば
ネジ兄さんや→
If only I knew where
their souls were located...
みんなを助けることができるのに。
I could save Neji and the others.
（シノ）ぐっ…。
シノ君！
Shino!
シノさん！
これ以上　あなたという貴重な
戦力を失うわけにはいきません。
You're an asset to our military strength!
We can't afford to lose you!
シノ君　もう…。
Shino, please!
俺はあきらめないぞ　ヒナタ。
シノ君。
I'm not giving up, Hinata.
Shino...
ネジやキバを助けるところまで
あと一歩なんだ。
We're just a step away
from saving Neji and Kiba.
俺があきらめてしまっては
そこへたどり着く前に→
If I give up,
the flame of hope will be extinguished
before we even reach them.
希望の火が途絶えてしまう。
（いの）あきらめるのは簡単よ。
Giving up is easy.
それがわかれば助かるなら
その方法をあきらめずに探すのよ。
If the only way to save them
is to find their location,
we can't give up.
We have to keep searching for them!
あきらめない。
I'm not giving up...
（ナルト）シカクのおっちゃん　シカマルたちに
何かあったのか？
Mister Shikaku!
Did something happen to
Shikamaru and the others?
あいつらのチャクラが
急に感じられなくなったんだ。
All of a sudden,
I stopped sensing their chakra!
俺にできることがあるんなら
言ってくれ。
Tell me if there's anything I can do!
なんとか言ってくれよ！
Say something!
（いのいち）シカク。
Shikaku...
（シカク）ナルトにつないでくれ。
Connect me to Naruto.
《シカク：ナルト　聞こえるか？》
Naruto, can you hear me?
シカクのおっちゃん。　シカマルたちは
どうなってるんだってばよ。
Mister Shikaku!
What's happening to Shikamaru
and the guys?!
《あいつらにかけられた術が
わかった。
We know the jutsu
that they used.
黄泉転身といって　魂を
肉体から引きはがし→
It's the Underworld Transfer Jutsu
that extracts the soul from the victim's body
特殊な結界へと移す術だ》
and places it inside a special barrier.
魂を引きはがすって…。
けど　みんなはまだ生きてんだろ。
Extracts the soul?
But they're all still alive, right?
だったら
魂の位置を探し出して…。
Then find the location
of the souls and...
《無理だ。　魂の位置なんて
特定できる忍はいない》
That's impossible...
There's no shinobi
who can locate souls.
俺にできることは？
お前は　今や→
What can I do?
Right now, you are the only shinobi
忍連合の混乱を救える
唯一の忍だ。
who can mitigate the chaos
within the Allied Forces.
いかにお前のチャクラが膨大でも
戦場すべてを網羅するのは不可能。
No matter how immense
your chakra,
there's no way you can
cover every battlefront.
今だって相当無理をしているはず。
You're stretching yourself thin as it is.
たかが４人のために　貴重な
戦力であるお前をさく余裕は→
At this point,
the Allied Forces can't spare
an important military asset
like you for just four shinobi.
今の忍連合にはない。
バカ野郎！　たかがじゃねえ！
You idiot! They're not "just" shinobi!
シカマルはおっちゃんの
息子じゃねえか！
Shikamaru is your son!
聞いたぜ。　シノも　いのも→
I heard how Shino and Ino are
desperately doing their best to save them!
必死であいつらを助けようって
頑張ってる。
親のあんたが見捨てんのかよ！
You're his father! How can you
turn your back on them?!
《俺は作戦を考え
指示する側の人間だ。
As the strategist,
I must coordinate everyone's actions.
勝手な行動は許されない。
I cannot allow people
to go off on their own.
お前の任務は敵の悪意を感知し
発見することだ。
Your duty is to identify the enemy
by sensing their malice.
全力で任務にあたってくれ》
You must do your absolute best.
ふざけんな！
（いのいち）ナルト！
Give me a break!
Naruto!
シカクは全力で任務にあたれと
言ったんだ。　わかるか？
Shikaku said to put every effort
into your mission.
Do you understand?
任務　了解だってばよ！
Roger on the mission!
always chasing after your shadow
itsu made mo oikakete iru anata no zanzo wo
when you dream, your face looks like it did before
yume ni miru yokogao ha ano koro no mama de
you run into the tall grass and disappear
se no takai kusanami ni hashiri satte kieta
I push through the memories and follow you
omoidasu kioku wo kakewake atoo uboku ha
it's frustrating as I run out of breath and in the end I'm unable to reach you
modokashiku mo iki wo kirashite saigo ha todokazu ni
far away
tooku
how many years ago was it?
nannenmae no koto desho
I left my heart at that place
nidoto modorenai ano basho ni
where I can never return
oite kite shimatta boku no kokoro sa
if this is a dream, if I can't get it back
moshimo yume naraba tori modosenai no nara
then how can I tell you how I feel?
kono kimochi ha do shite utaereba ii no
I'm still chasing after the shadow from that day
imadani oikakete iru ano hi no zanzo wo
though I spend my days in sorrow
kanashimi ni ake kurenagara mo ima
I'll live on in this world without you
anata naki sekai de boku wa ikiru yo
The Vengeful
（右近）あきらめろ。
さっきも言ったが俺たちは不死だ。
Give it up!
Like I told you earlier,
we're immortal.
（多由也）そのうちらを
仮に倒せたとしても→
And even if you do beat us,
this barrier won't come down.
この結界は解けない。
（鬼童丸）
ハッ　どうすることもできんぜよ。
There's nothing you can do.
（左近）フン…。
バカが…　まる見えだぜ！
What an idiot.
You're wide open!
（ネジ）八卦空掌！
8 Trigrams Air Palm!
（鬼童丸）チッ。
（キバ）牙通牙！
Fang Over Fang!
（多由也）あっ。
チッ！
《フッ　二度とリバウンドできないように
チャクラ食らいつくしてやりな》
Eat up his chakra
so that he can never
get back on his feet!
（チョウジ）うわっ！
今だ　左近！
Now, Sakon!
《シカマル：影寄せの術！》
Shadow Pull Jutsu!
バカが！　何やってんだ！？
That fool! What is he doing?!
うまくいったぜ。
あんだけ　でけえ門だからな→
It worked!
It's such a huge gate,
足場を崩せば　どうかと思ったが
ドンピシャだぜ！
I wondered what would happen
if it lost its foundation.
It's dead on!
てめえら
そこを攻撃させるために！？
Why you...
You made us attack that area?!
（右近）わざと狙ったってのか！？
ヘヘッ。
You were aiming for
that all along?
チッ！
クソが！
Damn... you bastards!
（シカマル）絶体絶命？　脱出不可能？
Cornered?
Escape is impossible?
だからって　あきらめられっかよ。
As if all that would
make us give up.
ナメやがって　ゲスチン野郎が！
You're underestimating us,
you pieces of crap!
ナメてるのは
おめえたちのほうだぜ。
No, you're underestimating us!
前やったときは
もっと強かったと思ったが…。
I thought you were
much stronger last time.
おっと
俺たちが成長したってことか？
Hey, does that mean
that we've improved,
死人は成長しねえからなぁ。
since the dead don't?
（キバ）まったくだぜ！
（赤丸）ワン！
Sounds about right!
（次郎坊）野郎　言わせておけば！
You and your big mouth!
シカマル　わざわざ敵を
あおることもあるまい。
Shikamaru...
No need to rile up
the enemy like that.
だいたいがよ
お前ら穢土転生ってのは→
Besides, you Reanimations were
called back to be tools of war, right?
戦争の道具として
呼び出されたんだろ？
それが　なんだって復讐なんて
くだらねえことするんだ？
So what's all this stupid stuff
about revenge?
そもそも
キバと俺は復讐相手でもねえ。
Why are you directing it at us?
やったのは　風の姉弟たちだろ？
Didn't the Sand siblings kill you?
俺たちが戦争の道具？　ククク…。
Us? Tools of war?
（右近）ククク…。
俺たちは
この戦争とは関係ないぜよ。
We have nothing to do
with this war!
この穢土転生は
大蛇丸様への誓いの証し。
Our Reanimation is simply proof
of our loyalty to Lord Orochimaru...
大蛇丸様が
約束を守ってくださった結果…。
Lord Orochimaru kept
his promise to us,
and this is the result.
((大蛇丸：さぁ　殺し合いなさい。
Now kill each other off.
本気で　やり合わなければ
どのみち私が殺すわよ。
If you're not serious about it,
I shall kill you.
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
（大蛇丸）死の恐怖をこえた先に
生まれる感情→
The feeling that is born when
one gets past the fear of death...
それよ　私が欲しかったものは。
That's what I wanted.
いい眼になったわね。
Look at those fine eyes.
あなたたちには
今以上の力を与えてあげる。
I shall bestow upon you
even greater power.
私のお気に入りとして
働いてもらうためにもね。
And you shall do my bidding
as my favored ones.
(（４人）忍法　四紫炎陣！))
– Ninja Art! Four Flames Formation!
（左近）俺たちは大蛇丸様のそばで
さまざまな忍術を見てきた。
We've witnessed various ninjutsu
at Lord Orochimaru's side.
その究極こそが　穢土転生。
The ultimate is...
The Reanimation.
((大蛇丸：うぅ…
あの老いぼれめ　よくも！
That old geezer... How dare he?!
ハァハァ…　何か言いたそうね？
It seems like you want
to say something?
（左近）いえ。
No...
今の私なら
あなたたちでも殺せるわ。
In my current state,
you can kill me.
やるなら今しかないわよ。
This is the time to do it,
if you so wish.
フッ…　そうね。
呪印で縛られている以上→
Well, I guess as long as
the Curse Mark binds you,
私に刃向かうことなど
できるはずもなかったわね。
you cannot point your blade at me.
失敗に終わったとはいえ→
Although you failed,
you made yourselves useful
木の葉崩しで
お前たちは役に立った。
in the destruction
of the Hidden Leaf.
何か褒美をとらせましょう。
望みを言いなさい。
I shall reward you.
What do you wish for?
（左近）望むものは決まっています。
（次郎坊）力…　忍としての力。
There is only one thing.
Power... Power as a shinobi.
それ以外　望むべくもない。
We wish for nothing more.
いいわね
あなたたち　すごくいいわ。
Fine...
You are all amazing.
叶えてあげましょう。
カブト　彼らをサンプルに加えなさい。
I shall grant your wish.
Kabuto, add them to the sample.
（カブト）わかりました。
I understand.
あなたたちの次なる力を
引き出すのは　復讐心。
A vengeful heart will draw out
the next level of power within you.
究極の復讐心が　呪印の力を
飛躍的に高めてくれるわ。
An extreme desire for revenge
rapidly increases
the power of the Curse Mark.
それと穢土転生と
どういう関係があるぜよ？
What's the connection between
that and Reanimation?
あの実験場で　死の恐怖を
乗り越えたあなたたちが得た感情。
The emotions you four learned
from overcoming the fear of death
at that laboratory...
それは私への恨み　憎しみ。
are bitterness and
hatred toward me.
いえ　もっと強い感情。
No, it was a much stronger emotion.
いつか私に
復讐してやろうと思ったはず。
I'm sure you swore
you would get back at me some day.
殺されるかもしれない…。
Even if you were killed in the process.
それだけで　そこまで誰かを
恨むことができるのならば→
When you can hate
someone that much,
本当に殺されたとき
あなたたちは　殺した相手を→
when you are actually killed,
you take it with you...
That hatred toward
the one who killed you.
恨みながら死んでいく。
甦ることができるのなら→
You die thinking that if
you could be resurrected,
it would be to only seek revenge.
そいつに復讐したいと思いながら。
あなたたちは　穢土転生によって
復讐者として　よみがえる。
Yes, through Reanimation,
you will be resurrected as
ones who seek vengeance.
その時　これまで知らなかった
更なる力を手に入れる。
And at that time, you will
attain power you never had before.
その力の源は
相手を憎悪する復讐心。
And the source of the strength
will be your consuming
desire for vengeance...
(手に入れた力を
存分に楽しむといいわ))
Take full pleasure in
your newfound power.
（左近）俺たちは
今も昔も大蛇丸様のもの！
Today, as in the past,
we belong to Lord Orochimaru!
（鬼童丸）いわば
大蛇丸様お墨付きの復讐者ぜよ。
We are Lord Orochimaru's
own vengeance seekers!
お前たちへの憎しみが　恨みが
俺たちの力を解放してくれる。
Our hatred and our bitterness
toward you release our power.
こうなりゃ誰にも止められねえぜ。
As it is now, no one can stop us.
そこらの穢土転生野郎とうちらを
一緒にすんなよ。　ゲスチンどもが！
Don't lump us into
the same category
as those other damn Reanimations,
you pieces of crap!
（チョウジ）そ…　そんな…。
Th-That's...
マジかよ！？
俺たちに復讐するためだけに→
Are you serious?
You were reanimated just
to get revenge against us?
よみがえったってのか？
（ネジ）まともじゃない。
You're crazy.
（シカマル）今の話がほんとなら→
If what they said is true...
本気モードは
これからってことかよ。
then they're just starting
to get serious...
うわっ！
気失うには　まだ早ぇだろうが！
It's too soon...
to faint!
うわ～っ！
おっ！？
ハハハッ！
柔拳も
レベルアップした蜘蛛粘金の前では→
Even the Gentle Fist is nothing
against my improved
Gum Style Spider Thread!
どうってことないぜよ！
ハハハッ！　俺は
もともと　シューティングより→
I've always been better
at grappling than shooting.
格ゲーのほうが得意ぜよ！
（キバ）牙狼牙！
Wolf Fang Over Fang!
やったか？
Did we get him?
（右近）おいおい　冗談だろ。
Hey, you must be joking!
この程度で　やられっかよ。
As if that degree of power
will have any effect.
今度は　こっちの番だぜ～！
Now, it's our turn!
ハハッ　最高だぜ　この呪印の力はよ。
The power of this Curse Mark
is amazing!
細胞融合と　かい離が
超速で　できるぜ！
Super quick cell fusion and
cell division are possible!
（多由也）
影に縛られるってことはよ→
So being bound by shadows
means stuff like this is possible?
こういうことも
できるってわけか？　フフッ。
うわっ！
弱すぎるんだよ　ゲスチンどもが。
You're too weak,
you pieces of crap!
調子に乗りやがって…。
Show off...
もはや
人間のレベルではない。
They've surpassed
the level of humans now.
（シカマル）ヘッ　ヘヘッ。
どうだい？　気は済んだかよ…。
So did you get it out of your system?
なに　余裕ぶっこいてんだよ。
Don't act so complacent.
おめえが死んでねえのは
手加減してやってるからだぞ。
The only reason
why you're not dead
is because we're going
easy on you!
殺したくて　たまらねえのを
我慢してんだよ！
I'm holding back
my irresistible urge to kill you!
そこを何とか
俺だけでも助けてくれよ。
About that...
Let me go. Just let me go.
ハハハ　いいね　そのツラ。
憎しみが１００倍増したぜ。
You've got balls...
My hatred just grew
a hundred times bigger.
ヘッ　そんなに
俺が憎いかよ。　あ～あ。
So you hate me that much?
Yeah.
なぜ　やけに敵を挑発するんだ？
（シカマル）チョウジ。
Why are you provoking her so much?
Choji...
ここに来る前に　俺たちが
話してたことを覚えてるか？
Do you remember
what we were talking about
before we got here?
え…。
Huh?
((幸い　本部は　変化のやつを
見分ける作戦を用意してる。
Luckily, HQ has a strategy
using a guy who can
see through the fakes.
(本部の作戦があるの？))
HQ has a strategy?
うん　でも　それが…。
Uh-huh... But what about it?
（シカマル）ありゃ　ナルトの力を
借りるってことなんだ。
The strategy is to
utilize Naruto's power.
ナルトが手に入れた　感知能力は→
Seems the sensory power Naruto
obtained enables him to sense evil.
悪意を感じとるものらしい。
そこで　みんなには
まだ知らせてなかったが→
They haven't notified
everyone about it yet.
ナルトは今　影分身で　各戦場に
増援に向かってるってわけだ。
Naruto's heading to
each of the battlefields now
with his Shadow Clones.
（多由也）おらっ！
ぐはっ！
Hey!
Shikamaru!
シカマル！
なに勝手にしゃべってんだよ！
What are you rambling about?!
すまねえ　今回ばかりは
俺も　勘なんだが→
Sorry.
This is one time
I'm going by intuition.
そろそろだと思うんだ。
But I have a feeling it'll be soon.
（シカマル）俺たちが　まともに
やり合う必要がねえ→
The third reason why
we don't need to fight directly...
３つめの理由…　あいつなら　必ず
この場所に気づいてくれる。
Knowing him, he's definitely
going to find this place.
それに　かけてみたのさ。
I'm just betting on that.
（みんな）あぁっ！
– What?!
うわっ！
いのいちのおっちゃん
やっぱあったぜ！
Mister Inoichi!
You were right!
どす黒い悪意をたどったら
すんげえ結界があったんだ。
I went toward
a pitch-black aura of evil
and there was a giant barrier!
《いのいち：あとは任せろ　ナルト。
Leave the rest to us, Naruto!
場所さえわかれば
シカマル君たちを助け出せる！
As long as we know
where they are,
we can save Shikamaru
and the others!
いいな　シカク》
Right, Shikaku?
《シカク：現場の判断に任せる》
Naruto, I'll leave you to deal
with the barrier.
ようし！
All right...
（ネジ）そうか　相手の悪意を
よむために→
I get it.
You kept provoking them
to make it possible for him
to sense their malice.
シカマルは　わざと挑発を…。
（キバ）ナルトが　そいつに
気づいてくれると信じて。
You had faith that
Naruto would pick it up.
（チョウジ）うん！
Yeah!
確かに　あんたらは強ぇ。
No doubt about it,
you guys are strong.
けど　同じ過ちを犯したんだ。
But you made
the same mistake again.
俺たちは
一人で戦ってるわけじゃねえ。
We aren't fighting alone.
ピンチのときに助け合ってきた
仲間だからこそ→
We have comrades
who rescued us
when we were in
a difficult situation.
That's why when
we're in a difficult situation now,
ピンチのときは　駆けつけてくれると
信じられる。
we can have faith that
they'll come to help us!
踏ん張ってさえいれば
希望は　必ずあると信じて。
We know that
as long as we stand firm,
there's always hope.
それが　仲間同士の絆。
That's the bond between comrades.
あんたらは　それに負けたんだ。
That's what beat you guys!
前回も　そして　今回も。
The last time...
and this time too!
We haven't lost yet!
まだ　負けたわけじゃないぜよ！
このパワー　かわすことも
受け止めることも　不可能ぜよ！
You can't break or stop this power!
It's impossible!
シカマル！
あぁ！
Shikamaru!
Yeah!
よし　つながった！
Good, we're connected!
（いのいち）解！
Release!
（次郎坊）てめえは…。
（鬼童丸）あん時のガキぜよ！
You're...!
That brat from last time!
（左近）バカな　この結界を
外から破るだと！？
Ridiculous!
He tore apart the barrier
from the outside?!
This is bad, Sakon.
（右近）まずいぞ　左近
結界が崩壊したら→
If the barrier is broken,
our souls will...
俺たちの魂が…。
ヘッ　その前に　こいつにだけでも
復讐してやろうぜ。
Before that, let's get our revenge
on this guy at least!
（４人）やぁ～！
復讐からは　何も生まれねえよ。
Nothing is born out of vengeance...
Our... souls!
（左近）俺たちの　魂が！
《カブト：死者の復讐心が
呪印に与える影響…。
The influence of the dead's desire
for revenge on the Curse Mark...
データが収集できただけでも
よしとするか。
Well, the data I collected
was worth it.
それに　そろそろ　あいつを
戦場に投入できそうだし。
I think pretty soon
I'll be able to put him out
into the battlefield...
そうなれば　これまでの前座なんて
どうでもよくなるしね》
And when that happens...
all these opening acts
will mean nothing.
《今回は　敵の悪意を
上手く利用できたけど→
This time, I was able to use
the enemy's evil intent
to our advantage,
戦争の悪意は
どんどん広がってる。
but the malice of war
is spreading like wildfire...
早いとこ　終わらせねえと》
I have to put an end
to this quickly.
hitomi tojite kokyuu tomete kasanariae futatsu no kage yo
closing my eyes, holding my breath, overlap two shadows
hikare hikare hikare sayonara namida
shine, shine, shine, goodbye tears
hitomi tojite
closing my eyes...
naki yamu koto no nai sora aoku tsutsumu machi wo
we once stood side by side gazing at
itsuka futari de narande nagameteta
the tear-drenched sky that wrapped the city in blue
mimi wo sumaseba
if I listen carefully
ima mo kimi no koe ga kikoeru
I can still hear your voice
mouichido dake ano koro mitai ni
hold me once more
dakiyosete yo
just like that time
nee waratte kocchi muite namae yonde ichido dake de ii
please smile, look at me, call my name, just once more
hikare hikare hikare sayonara namida
shine, shine, shine, goodbye tears
toki wo tomete negai komete ai wo tomenaide konya dake wa
stop the time, I wish with all my heart, don't stop love, just for this night
maware maware maware sayonara memorii
turn around, turn around, turn around, goodbye memory
hitomi tojite
closing my eyes...
Are you okay Neji?
My eyes have
recovered considerably,
but I still have
a lot of blind spots.
Please rest assured.
＜旬の魚が大好きな豆助＞
Until your eyes heal completely,
I'll protect you, Neji...
The way you protected me
back then.
When I protected you?
豆助　きょうのお魚は
今が旬のアレよ
This was back when Sasuke
was still in the village.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Heart's Eye"
＜　その魚とは？＞
I've always wanted to tell you,
to let you know.
＜　それは姿や味が周く…＞